字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
OCTOBER 1013 A.D. LONDON, ENGLAND
（西元1013年10月，英格蘭，倫敦）
EPISODE 9: THE FIGHT FOR LONDON BRIDGE
第9集：倫敦橋的死鬥
It's like a bridge.
與其說是橋
But it's really more of a fort.
不如說是要塞
That's London for you.
真不愧是倫敦
As a city, it's resisted attacks for years.
這座城市可是抵擋了多年的攻擊
I can feel its history.
我能感覺到它的歷史
This isn't the time to get sentimental, Askeladd.
現在不是說風涼話的時候，阿謝拉特
This city will give us trouble.
這座城市很棘手呢
I'm here because you said it'd be an easy victory.
都是你說很輕鬆，我才參加的
Sorry about that.
抱歉了
But I never thought that we'd be facing Thorkell as our enemy.
但我完全沒想到 得面對托魯克爾當我們的敵人
Thorkell the Tall?
高個子托魯克爾？
He joined London's side for money.
他竟然為了錢幫助倫敦
That traitor.
叛徒一個
We're the same when it comes to money.
我們不也是為了錢嗎？
I joined the Danes because I thought King Sweyn had a good chance of winning.
我加入丹麥軍隊 是因為我認為斯韋恩王有勝算
Other clans feel the same.
其他部族也一樣
They're all desperate to achieve greatness and get their share of the spoils.
他們都拚命想立功，希望分到戰利品
Well, it won't be much with so many gathered here.
不過有這麼多人 應該也分不到多少戰利品吧
I don't go to war for the money.
我不是為了錢而戰的
I just like killing.
我只是喜歡殺人而已
I can always count on you, Bjorn.
我就知道你很靠得住，表倫
Well, our leaders want to take a rich city like London.
不過上頭的人很想拿下 像倫敦這樣富裕的城市
If they gain control of the River Thames,
如果控制住泰晤士河
they can establish a supply route inland to Wessex.
就能掌握通往威塞克斯內陸的補給線
So this battlefield is being carefully watched?
所以他們很重視這場戰役，對吧？
That's right. If there's one place you can stand out, it's here.
沒錯，真想立功的話就看這戰了
That's right.
真是的
Do you have a fun strategy in mind?
你想到什麼有趣的策略了嗎？
It's not really a strategy.
也不算是策略啦…
Thorfinn!
托爾芬！
Time to go to work.
該做事了
Bring me Thorkell's head.
把托魯克爾的首級拿來給我
Promise me a reward.
答應給我獎賞
Okay.
好啊
The usual, right?
還是老樣子吧？
You never change, do you?
你永遠不會改變，對吧？
You go all in on fights you can't win. That's where you're just like your father.
老是拚盡全力打你贏不了的仗
Do not forget, Askeladd.
別忘了，阿謝拉特
My only desire is to crush you in a duel as warriors.
身為戰士，我唯一的心願 就是在決鬥中打敗你
The next duel will be your last.
下一場決鬥會是你的最後一場
I will rip out your heart and offer it to my father's spirit.
我要把你的心臟挖出來 獻給我爸的在天之靈
Then go to work.
那就好好做事吧
We must do our job on the battlefield before getting what we want.
只有在戰場上完成任務的人 能獲得他想要的獎賞
That is how warriors do things.
這就是戰士的作風
My head doesn't come cheap.
我的首級可不便宜
I won't just duel you over and over again.
要決鬥多少次我都答應你
Go get Thorkell's head.
只要你把托魯克爾的首級取來
Hey!
喂！
Askeladd!
阿謝拉特！
Huh?
什麼事？
There's a ship approaching the bridge.
有艘船往橋那裡開過去了
It's the Jomsviking ship — Stag of the Sea.
是約姆戰士團的海鹿號
That's the regiment's envoy.
那是軍團的使者吧
So it's Floki.
是弗洛基嗎？
He'll offer twice the amount the English are paying him.
他打算付比英格蘭人多一倍的價格
He'll try to win Thorkell over.
拉攏托魯克爾吧
Thorkell follows the money.
托魯克爾唯利是圖
He'll take it, won't he?
他會接受吧？
Let's wait and see what he does.
我們就來看看他會怎麼做
Here they come! Just one ship!
他們來了！只有一艘船！
This way! Quickly!
這邊！快點！
Die, you bastards!
去死吧，混蛋！
Come on! Take them down!
快點幹掉他們！
Shoot!
放箭！
Don't shoot! We're an envoy.
不要攻擊！我們是使者
We wish to speak to Thorkell.
我們想和托魯克爾談一談
-Take this! -Damn you!
-看招！ -去你的！
Die!
去死吧！
We did not come to fight!
我們不是來跟你們打的！
Where is Thorkell?
托魯克爾在哪裡？
Shut up and die!
閉嘴，去死吧！
Wait.
喂
Stop.
住手
Alright.
是
All of you, cease your attack!
全都停止攻擊！
Hey, Floki! It's been a long time!
弗洛基，好久不見！
Glad to see you looking so well.
很高興看到你還是這麼硬朗
Enough pleasantries!
不用客套了！
We've come to relay a message from our supreme commander.
我們來替首領斯韋恩王陛下傳話
His Majesty King Sweyn sends this message.
國王陛下說
"The King of England has fled to the land of the Franks.
“英格蘭王已逃到法蘭克王國
It is pointless to continue your opposition.
繼續抵抗已經毫無意義
Surrender,
投降吧
and in the name of the god Thor,
我以提爾神之名發誓
you and your subordinates will be guaranteed your lives and assets."
我會保證你 和手下的性命和財產安全”
Come back to our army, Thorkell!
回來軍團吧，托魯克爾！
That is the wish of His Majesty the King.
國王陛下也希望你回來
Is King Sweyn here?
斯韋恩王來了嗎？
He sure works hard for a man of his age.
他都一把年紀了，還真是拚命
Thorkell!
托魯克爾！
Why are you still pointing your arrows at your friends?
都這種時候了 你為什麼要對同胞箭矢相向？
Have we not spent many years fighting wars side by side?
我們不是多年來 一起並肩作戰的戰友嗎？
Don't be swept away by the wrong current.
你可不要誤判情勢
Your elder brother Sigvaldi is also concerned about you.
你哥哥席古瓦帝大人也很擔心你
Wrong current?
情勢啊？
I see.
說得也是
I know who've I've joined. I fought against them last year.
我直到去年還與英格蘭人為敵 所以我知道
They really are weak.
這些傢伙真的很弱
-A bunch of city weaklings. -What'd he say?
-不過就是一群都市出生的弱者… -什麼？
Is he speaking Norse?
他在說諾斯語嗎？
Probably.
應該吧
The only man who could stand against the Danish army
唯一能與丹麥軍隊勢均力敵的
is probably Prince Edmund.
大概只有艾德蒙王子吧
This country is falling apart.
這個國家完蛋了
So in that case…
這樣的話…
Yes, which means…
對，這就表示…
it's far more interesting
跟你們戰鬥有趣多了！
The conversation's over!
話就說到這！
Resume the attack!
我們繼續吧！
Wait!
等等！
Thorkell!
托魯克爾！
If you join us now, we'll gladly double what the English promised you!
如果你現在就加入我們 我們會付比英格蘭多一倍的酬勞給你
Bring it on, Floki!
來打吧，弗洛基！
Evade! Veer full speed to the left!
快避開！全速往左！
The Ultimate Keel Wrecker!
必殺，龍骨碎！
Oh no, I missed?
哎呀，沒打中？
Full speed! Break away!
全速前進！快逃！
Men, take them down.
發射吧
Yes, sir!
-遵命！
Retreat!
撤退！
Hey, Floki!
喂，弗洛基！
Ask King Sweyn for me,
幫我問問斯韋恩王
if he's grown tired of always winning.
他老是打勝仗是不是很無聊！
There was no indication that he could be convinced.
他無意接受我們的條件
I see.
這樣啊
How irritating.
真是煩人
What shall we do?
我們該怎麼辦？
Attack once again immediately.
立刻再次攻擊
Shit!
可惡！
All right!
來吧！
Damn! They've reached the bridge.
可惡，他們到橋邊了
That bastard!
那個混蛋！
Hurry!
快點！
Damn it!
可惡！
No! We're not hitting them!
可惡，都沒打中他們！
Bring more stones!
多拿點石頭來！
Out of the way.
讓開！
Amazing.
好厲害
Here you go!
接招吧！
Did you see that?
看到沒有？這是我的必殺技，圓…
That's my Ultimate Log Drop!
要叫什麼…木墜！
-That's how it's done. -Impressive.
-就是那樣！ -不過真厲害
Next!
下一個！快點！
Yes, sir!
-是
What's wrong, army of Sweyn?
斯韋恩軍隊，怎麼了？
Is that all you got?
放馬過來啊！
If you try harder, I think you can do it!
再努力一點就行了！
But at this rate,
但照這樣下去
it'll take 100 years before London bridge…
再花一百年也攻不下這倫敦橋…
Here comes someone interesting.
來了個有趣的人
Thorfinn, can you hear me?
托爾芬，聽得到嗎？
See the giant up front with the log up?
看到最前面那個扛木頭的巨人沒？
That's Thorkell!
他就是托魯克爾！
It's no use! Halt the ship!
沒用的！停船！
If we get any closer, we'll be killed!
再靠近的話我們就死定了！
Rotate to the left!
左轉！
Hold out a little longer!
再撐一下！
All right, that's enough!
好，夠近了！
Jump!
跳吧！
None of you lay a hand on him!
你們都別碰他！
This happy-go-lucky fool…
那個不知天高地厚的笨蛋…
is mine!
是我的！
Here we go!
來吧！
Bastard.
混蛋
You can fight,
你很會打嘛
young one.
小夥子
Nobody touch him.
你們都別出手
I must answer his surprise attack myself.
我得回應他的突襲才行
It's a one-on-one fight!
這是一對一的對戰！
Come at me, little one!
放馬過來吧，小不點！
One-on-one with bare fists…
徒手一對一…
He's mocking me.
他在嘲笑我
He was aiming for my wrist?
他瞄準了我的手腕？
Nice one, little man.
不錯嘛，小傢伙
No wonder he's confident.
難怪他那麼有自信
I'm dead if that giant…
要是被那個巨人的拳頭打中 我就死定了
I like you!
我喜歡你！
This old man is all fired up!
我這老頭要火力全開了！
What?
什麼？
Oops!
糟糕！
That was a close one.
還真是千鈞一髮
I can't reach him.
我刺不到他
His weak spots are too high up.
他的要害太高了
His armpit, his neck…
腋下、脖子…
All right.
好
He's low.
他壓低身體了
In that case,
這樣的話
I'll kick him!
我就用踢的！
I'll get in close!
衝上去！
Oh dear…
哎呀…
Ouch, that hurts!
好痛！
But now, I've caught you!
但我抓住你了！
-He got him! -That's it, Captain!
-抓住他了！ -就是這樣，老大！
Kill him!
殺了他！
Not yet!
還沒完呢！
All right!
來吧！
God damin it.
真是的
This is no good.
這下不妙
Thorfinn's getting his ass kicked.
托爾芬被打成肉泥了
I guess it was impossible after all.
果然還是打不過他
Askeladd, that's the signal.
阿謝拉特，那是撤退的信號
Oh, it's time to retreat.
那就該撤退了
Retreat!
撤退！
All battalions withdraw!
全軍撤退！
Oh, no.
糟了
The battle finished as I was playing with the little one.
和小不點玩耍的時候，戰役就結束了
Oh, it seems they've abandoned you.
看來他們拋棄了你，可憐的傢伙
And you gave it your all.
你也盡力了
Oh, is he dead?
死了嗎？
Hey!
喂！
You still have your fighting spirit.
你還沒喪失鬥志啊
For a small soldier, you're very impressive.
就一個小兵來說還滿厲害的嘛
Warrior, what is your name?
戰士，你叫什麼名字？
Thorfinn.
托爾芬
I am Thorfinn, son of Thors.
我是托爾茲之子托爾芬
Thors?
托爾茲？
By "Thors," do you mean--
喂，托爾茲是…
Oh my, he's gone.
可惡，他跑掉了
What do we do, Captain?
老大，怎麼辦？
Shoot him?
要射箭嗎？
No.
不用
We'll let him go for today.
今天就放他一馬
Hey! Warrior Thorfinn!
喂，戰士托爾芬！
That was fun!
我玩得很開心！
Let's do it again!
有機會再一起玩！
Next time, we'll finish this!
下次要一決勝負喔！
That's a promise!
說定了喔！
It hurts…
好痛
Kill me please…
殺了我吧
Does anyone want to be finished off?
有誰想死的嗎？
I can do mercy killings.
我可以成全他
This one's no good.
這傢伙不行了
He's been gutted.
腸子都被劃破了
He can't be saved.
他沒救了
Hey! Bring some onion soup over here!
喂，拿點洋蔥湯過來這裡！
Torgrim! Deal with this one.
托格利姆，送這個人上路
I see.
我知道了
London won't fall.
倫敦攻不下來
No, it's not that it won't fall.
不，並不是攻不下來
We just need more time.
我們只是還需要一點時間
How much time, Floki?
弗洛基，還需要多少時間？
Well, depending on how much they've stockpiled…
這要看倫敦的軍糧儲備量
it could take a year.
可能需要一年…
No, if all goes well, half a year.
不，順利的話半年就可以
It's already autumn.
已經秋天了
We cannot waste time on just one city.
我們不能為了單單一個城市 花這麼多的時間
The overall outcome is what's important.
要以大局為重
No matter what, capturing all of England is the priority.
無論如何都必須 以掌控整個英格蘭為優先
Yes.
是
Have the main army move west.
讓主力軍往西移動
I will leave 4,000 soldiers to continue the siege of London.
留下四千名兵力繼續包圍倫敦
As you wish.
遵命
To command the 4,000…
這四千人的指揮官…
Yes, let's see…
我想…
I will leave it to Canute.
就交給庫奴特吧
It is a good opportunity to exhibit his prowess as a man.
這是個讓他展現男子氣概的好機會
What?
什麼？
But this is different from what we discussed?
這不是跟之前討論的不一樣嗎？
Didn't you say His Highness was brought along only to observe?
您不是說殿下與軍隊同行 只是為了作秀嗎？
Ragnar, stand down. This is His Majesty's will.
拉古納爾，別說了，這是陛下的旨意
The whole of the army can't beat Thorkell.
就連全軍出動都打不過托魯克爾
Fighting with only a fifth of our strength is impossible!
只留下五分之一的兵力更是不可能！
It would do him no good otherwise.
太容易的話要怎麼鍛鍊他？
But…
可是…
The battlefield will only compound His Highness's anxiety.
殿下還未習慣戰場 這樣只會讓殿下更為擔心
You're in part responsible for that, Ragnar.
你也有責任，拉古納爾
Perhaps the Christian teachings are at fault.
或許都要怪基督教吧
He has grown up peculiarly weak despite being a man.
但他身為男人，卻異常柔弱
You have spoiled him as his attendant.
都是你這個貼身隨從太寵他了
My…
非常抱歉
Appoint the siege regiment to Canute.
把負責包圍的軍隊交給庫奴特
As his attendant, you will be his second-in-command.
身為他隨從的你就擔任副將
His Highness…
殿下…
My shoulder is dislocated.
肩膀脫臼了
My right ankle is sprained.
右腳踝扭傷
And several ribs are broken.
還有幾根肋骨斷了
Damn that monster!
那個可惡的瘋子！
Hey, do you see them?
喂，看得到他們嗎？
Well,
這個嘛
most of them are withdrawing.
他們幾乎都離開了
Which means…
這就表示…
Did we win?
我們贏了？
-They hightailed it out of here. -Then that means we won.
他們夾著尾巴逃了？
What is this?
什麼？
What's going on?
怎麼回事？
We did it! We are victorious!
我們成功了！我們獲勝了！
What?
什麼？
Hey!
喂！
Keep fighting!
再繼續打啊！
Hey, wait!
喂，等等！
Hey!
喂！
You idiots!
你們這些白痴！
You're just conceding London?
你們就這樣放棄倫敦了嗎？
Come back, you cowards!
回來，你們這些膽小鬼！
Fight me!
來跟我打啊！
What a pain.
真是討厭
That bastard Thorkell.
托魯克爾那個混蛋
What happened to you? You ended up living.
喂，你怎麼了？你還活著？
Dear me, you're in a sorry state.
天啊，你被打得好慘
This time you had a difficult opponent, Thorfinn.
你這次遇到難纏的對手了，托爾芬
By the way, we are marching to Wessex. What will you do?
對了，我們要進軍威塞克斯了 你打算怎麼辦？
We'll leave you behind if you can't walk.
你要是走不動，我們就把你留在這裡
We'll get paid in Wessex!
我們要去威塞克斯賺錢！
-I'm itching for a fight. -Don't you only have one arm?
我迫不及待好好打一場了
I'll kill them.
我會殺了他們
That was fun!
我玩得很開心！
Let's do it again!
有機會再一起玩！
These damn monsters.
這些可惡的瘋子
What the hell…
戰爭到底哪裡有趣？